<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Digital Notebook - Probability Theory</title><link href="https://anmold-07.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://anmold-07.github.io/feeds/probability-theory.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://anmold-07.github.io/</id><updated>2019-12-01T19:30:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>References for Probability Theory and Applications</title><link href="https://anmold-07.github.io/2019/09/01/my-super-post/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-01T10:25:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-12-01T19:30:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Anmol</name></author><id>tag:anmold-07.github.io,2019-09-01:/2019/09/01/my-super-post/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;References for a course on Stochastic Signals and Systems&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The following references helped me understand important concepts in the field of, but not restricted to, probability theory, markov chains, time-series analysis etc. 
I hope these help you too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLbMVogVj5nJQqGHrpAloTec_lOKsG-foc"&gt;This playlist&lt;/a&gt; by Dr. Krishna Jagannathan from IIT Madras is an excellent reference for understanding the theory behind probability. This helped me become familiar with a lot sophisticated terms in the literature especially various concepts related to Borel-Cantelli lemmas and convergence of a sequence of random variables. These are quite abstract but explained beautifully in the lectures. Lecture Notes for this playlist can be found &lt;a href="http://www.ee.iitm.ac.in/~krishnaj/ee5110notes.htm"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gtribello.github.io/mathNET/SOR3012.html"&gt;This course&lt;/a&gt; on Stochastic Processes is an excellent reference that focuses on both theoretical and practical aspects of advanced probability theory. It best explains continuous and discrete time markov chains with numerous practical examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No reference is complete without MIT OCW's courses. &lt;a href="https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/electrical-engineering-and-computer-science/6-262-discrete-stochastic-processes-spring-2011/index.htm"&gt;This course&lt;/a&gt; provides a comprehensive overview of discrete time Stochastic Processes with very comprehensive lecture notes. References &lt;a href="http://math.mit.edu/~sheffield/fall2019math600.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; were also helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive reference for practice problems on probability theory can be found &lt;a href="https://courses.grainger.illinois.edu/ece313/fa2019/old_exams.html"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="probability"></category><category term="randomness"></category><category term="stochastic signls"></category></entry></feed>